Shubham Shilvane

Front-End Developer

Passionate Frontend Developer with overall 4 years of IT industry experience. Hands on experience with the concepts and implementations of HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap3&4, Javascript, AJAX, ES6, Flex and Angular, Angular material. Eagerly expanding skills into Backend, dedicated to ongoing learning and staying abreast of industry trends for proactive Developers.

x shubhamshilvane1296@gmail.com

Hyderabad, India

in linkedin.com/in/shubhamshilvane

+919637014535

vercel.com/shubhams-projects-bede0601

https://github.com/Shubham-96k

PORTFOLIO:

Shubham - A Web Developer

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Frontend Angular Developer

OSSS Consulting services Pvt Ltd. 05/2022-Present

Nizamabad, India

Key roles and responsibilities:

- Led the front-end development for an E-commerce domain, ensuring a seamless and user-friendly experience. The
 major services include sales of electrical accessories like transformers, solar panels, motors and batteries.
- Created different modules, components using Angular Material, pipes and directives in Angular as per business requirements.
- Implemented responsive web design techniques to ensure that the e-commerce website functions well across various
 devices and screen sizes, providing a consistent user experience on desktops, tablets, and smartphones.
- Implementation of different types of Quotation forms using reactive forms in Angular and TD form for Login and Signup Component.
- Optimized the frontend performance by applying best practices such as code splitting, lazy loading, and caching.
- Monitor and analyze website performance metrics (e.g., page load time, time to interact) to identify and address
 performance bottlenecks Overcame data integration challenges in the user module implementing a custom API,
 ensuring accurate and up-to-date information to users.

<u>Frontend Developer (XPORIENCE)</u>

OSSS Consulting services Pvt Ltd.

05/2021 - 05/2022

Nizamabad,India

Key roles and responsibilities:

- Converted PSD into responsive HTML using Bootstrap 3.
- Created interactions using JavaScript/jQuery.
- Used jQuery Plugins.
- Fixing issues raised by team.
- Responsive website for browser & environmental compatibility on every devices.

Application Support Engineer

OSSS Consulting services Pvt Ltd. 05/2020-05/2021

05/2020 - 05/2021 Nizamabad, India

Key roles and responsibilities:

- Coordinated with Level 1 technical support specialists to take over calls outside their level of support.
- Assisted customers with more difficult technical issues requiring a greater level of personalized care and in greater length.
- diagnose and troubleshoot software and hardware problems and help our clients install applications and programs.
- Escalated support desk tickets to Level 3 in the most crucial circumstances.
- On boarded and trained all incoming junior tech support specialists.

<u>ACHIEVEMENTS</u>

- Contributed Ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs and enhancements in the angular project received positive feedback from users, leading to 15% increase in user engagement.
- Received a lot of appreciation from the team for quick learning and implementation.
- Received a lot of appreciation from the client for smooth delivery of the project.

SKILLS:	Angular 10		Angular Material		ypeScript	JavaScript, ES6		CSS3	
	SASS	HTML5	Bootstr	rap(3&4)	AJAX	NGB	ootstrap	FLEX	
	RXJS	jQuery	NPM	GIT/GITH	HUB RW	VD I	Media Quer	ies	
TOOLS:	Visual studio Code Vercel Postman Firebase Jira jQuery-Plugins								
	Augury Chrome Developer Tool			· Tool	ANGULAF	R-CLI	FontAwe	esome	

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree

SRTMU Nanded

06/2017 - 11/2020

Intermediate (11th & 12th)

Swami Vivekanand College

06/2015 - 06/2017

Courses:

MPC (Mathematics & Statistics, Physics & Chemistry)

LANGUAGES

Marathi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Hindi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

English

FullProfessional Proficiency